PERSONAL INFORMATION

Julijana Prchkovska



Address: Razloska 7-2/26, 1000 Skopje (Macedonia)

Phone:+ 389 71 207 770 E-mail: m.julika@live.com

Date of birth: 05 July 1975

An exceptional combination of skills developed as a result of years long engagements in the IT publishing and marketing and promotion industries on executive and managerial positions. My technical skills and my passion for writing, psychology and self-improvement helped me to grow in to a professional educator and consultant. This diverse set of skills and my passion for the gender equality has empowered me to create a synergy between the IT and marketing worlds and allowed me to evolve my career as a top level executive responsible for brand communication, marketing, events organization and coordination with the unique gender sensitive access. At the same time my passion for entrepreneurship and intrapreneurship and my willingness to share my experience lead me to the mentoring and active participation in the CSO's as a great way to help all learners to improve their skills and achieve their full potential.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2015-Present

KOSID MG KONSALTING DOOEL SKOPJE

Small business consultant and mentor

Evaluation of the current status of small businesses and their teams and developing strategy on how they can improve their operations. Assisting in implementation of the strategy by using unique handholding and gender sensitive approach. Starting from idea challenge and finishing with personality challenge this approach allow developing an investor ready and market ready products and teams, prepared to answer to all threat of the business world. Developing specific trainings for the management and employees in order to build an effective team, by encouraging co-operation, teamwork, interdependence and by building trust among team members.

2011-2014

DIVISION, Skopje

Key account manager, Editor in Chief

Key account for the biggest clients in the agency. Serving as a link between the clients and the entire agency team by utilizing all resources to develop and implement strategic solutions to achieve key clients' long-term goals.

Marketing events executive. Merged my experience in organizing large events and leading

J.P. 2022

creative teams to plan and execute marketing and PR events for commercial clients in one of the leading marketing agencies in Macedonia.

In-house ICT magazine Enter, Editor in Chief, 2011 -2014

Restarted the in-house monthly ICT magazine brand Enter and launched a web portal under the same brand with daily content publishing from the ICT world. Writing articles and editing the whole content.

Participate in strategy development and supervise the execution of an extensive social media campaign for the magazine and web portal promotion.

2010–2011 Click MK - ICT magazine, Skopje

Editor in Chief

Developed content strategy for each publication. Managed a group of authors and monitored its everyday working. Monitored all content produced and ensured delivery within the time frame and of the highest quality. Coordination with advertisers, preparation of an editorial calendar and development of a calendar in line with company objectives. Design various advertising strategies to provide support to content team.

1997–2009 PLUGIN PC WORLD MACEDONIA, MK Macedonian franchise of PC World, Skopje

Cofounder, Editor in Chief

Lead the magazine and website division, including direct supervision of 15 staff members and the Art Department. As a direct result of managing the direction, content, design, production and promotion of the magazine and website, we reached 10,000 readers across the country. I was also responsible for producing a variety of web based media, including e-newsletters, podcasts, webcasts, blog, and landing pages; Developed strategic alliances and partnerships with professional organizations, resulting in seminars, cross merchandising, content, and brand extension products.

As a first female leader in such a position I managed to start the change in biases and cultural stereotypes that discourage the women and girls to join the IT industry. Worked closely with the IT companies in order to understand the level of gender diversity in their business and created solutions to empower more women and girls in IT.

Worked closely in the first phase of company's digitalisation process and developed and implement a serial of training materials and trainings for XEROX DMS process digitalisation tools.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

1994–1996 Bachelor of Science/ Major: Institute of Pedagogy

UNIVERSITY ST. CYRILS AND METHODIUS, Faculty of Philosophy, Skopje (Macedonia)

1989–1994 High School Graduate

High School "Josip Broz Tito" Skopje, Skopje (Macedonia)

2007 Certified trainer

DOCUSHARE – Skopje, MK Leading DMS (Document Management System) by Xerox, Skopje (Macedonia)

Develop training modules for groups with various skill levels Organize teaching groups and

J.P. 2022

select/produce curriculums for different skill levels based on the group requirements. Emotional Intelligence development workshops and training for various public.

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s)

Macedonian

Foreign language(s)

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C1	C1	C1	C1	B2
C1	C1	C1	C1	C1

English Serbian

General skills

- Proficient in Microsoft Office Suite.
- Basic knowledge in graphic applications.
- Expert in Project Cycle Management
- Knowledgeable in project management tools, processes and techniques.
- Exemplary problem solving skills/ able to identify problems and create and implement corrective processes.
- Skilled at presenting technical and abstract concepts in a clear and concise way.
- Strong communication, interpersonal and presentation skills.
- Skilled in cultivating positive relationships with clients and colleagues; particularly adept at communicating with clarity and diplomacy to individuals from diverse cultural and organizational backgrounds.
- Excellent listener
- Passionate about achieving gender equality by eliminating all gender-based discrimination and gender stereotypes in all areas of life.

Projects Experience

- Kitchen on wheels project funded by IPA COMPONENT IV. (2015-2017)
 Providing Team development training for the project partner EASP Prilep.
 Monitoring the overall project implementation.
- EASP Prilep -restructuring process. (2017)
 - Evaluation of the organisation performance. Designing strategy for the interoperability and closer cooperation between EASP Skopje and EASP Prilep branch. Revision of the organisations goals and objectives. Creating strategy for gender sensitive approach in all segments of organisation activities. Development of training for the organisation members.
- ELIT Skopje- design of a capacity building strategy and training. (2018)
 Evaluation of the organisation performance and team performance. Designing a new project oriented strategy for the organisation which lead to finding new donors for their strategic objectives. Designing and implementing set of trainings for the ELIT members in project management tools and project funding.
- ELIT Skopje Women in Decision-making Positions, funded by the Ministry of

J.P. 2022

Economy of the Republic of North Macedonia. (2018)

Project implementation monitoring. Preparation of the final report. Project result dissemination.

Pro Dizajn -In Room Preview Project funded by the FITR

Project proposal design and implementation monitoring. Designing special training for the project team for project implementation process. Designing specific team building training and tools. Creating Marketing and internationalisation strategy.

 Platform - Women in Decision-making Positions, funded by the Ministry of Economy of the Republic of North Macedonia. (2020)

Project implementation monitoring. Preparation of the project report. Dissemination of the project results.

Rely on youth- Project funded by the EU (2022-2023)

Creating project strategy for ELIT as a project partner. Designing internal project management training for the ELIT Project assistant and ELIT project member team. Internal evaluation of the results.

J.P. 2022 Page 4 / 4